<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Generative Unity</title>
    <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Generative Unity</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/00_Introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/00_Introduction/</guid>
      <description>What is this book? The core idea of this book is teaching Unity as tool for creatives of all all kinds. This is “living” book. This means things will change, parts will grow, others will wither. This is for multiple reasons. For one, I am not an expert on all topics in Unity, especially not programming. I have background in Media-Design and merely am trying to learn and in this case teach Unity to the best of my ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/01_The_Editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/01_The_Editor/</guid>
      <description>Getting started with Unity So you managed your way through the Introduction and are still here. Awesome! The first step on your Journey to learn is to actually go and download Unity. While you could just head to unity3d.com and grab the latest and greatest Version of Unity Personal, I would suggest getting the Unity Hub. Unity Hub will help you manage your Projects as well as the Versions of Unity you have installed on your machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/02_Moving_Things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/02_Moving_Things/</guid>
      <description>On Design Throughout the first chapters we will use Josef Albers “Hommage to the Square” as a starting point for experimentation. This will be a great way to get started coding with small script and also see how just a few lines of code can change a lot of the feel of things. These two thing will perfetly go hand in hand, as Design, as well as Coding are Skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/03_The_Console/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/03_The_Console/</guid>
      <description>The Console - Your best friend This chapter is a short but important intermezzo. Maybe you have already encountered the console. Whenever you write code your computer does not understand it will tell you so in the console. And worse, it will also block you from running your code! As we are Coding in C# your computer will be very, very picky about the code you write. So if you haven’t already fabricated an error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/04_UserInput/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/04_UserInput/</guid>
      <description>Conditionals So we kow how to code some absolute basic movement. But that’s built upon the conveneience of the Sin Function and that’s really rather limited. So what if we could do things based off of some condition. Let’s say you press a button, move the mouse or tilt your phone? This is where Conditionals come in. Conditionals are one way to manage how your code is flowing (”Control Flow”).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/05_Functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/05_Functions/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/05_MultipleObjects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/05_MultipleObjects/</guid>
      <description>Title: Master
Author:
Multiple Object Workflow If you followed along with some of the examples, you probably realized we are doing a lot of manual labor in changing things on the Unity Editor itself. Each Square has to get the new Script and so forth. Then again programming is a lazy mans art. The less manual labor we have to the better. In this Chapter we will introduce ways to handle multiple Squares at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/06_MultipleObjects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/06_MultipleObjects/</guid>
      <description>Multiple Object Workflow If you followed along with some of the examples, you probably realized we are doing a lot of manual labor in changing things on the Unity Editor itself. Each Square has to get the new Script and so forth. Then again programming is a lazy mans art. The less manual labor we have to do the better. In this Chapter we will introduce ways to handle multiple Squares at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/98_AdditionalResources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/98_AdditionalResources/</guid>
      <description>Title: Master
Author:
Addtional Resources You finished everything ans ask yourself: What’s next? My style of writing isn’t yours? These are rescources which are somewhat related to the topic, but can ben written for other programming languages or software. Yet they still hold - in my eyes -tremendous value. So feel free to check them out!
Books: - The nature of Code - Daniel Shiffman - Eloquent Javascript - Marijn Haverbeke - Graphic Deisgn: The New Basics - Ellen Lupton, Jennifer Cole Phillips</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/99_Github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/docs/99_Github/</guid>
      <description>Let’s talk about Version Control You probably noticed, or will soon, that sometimes you have an idea on how to improve your code. You reformat your code, delete some old code here some there and all is good. The next day you look at your code an realize that it was laaate last night and everything you did, was just breaking stuff. But what did you actually change last night?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/posts/01_The_Editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeunity.henrikgieselmann.com/posts/01_The_Editor/</guid>
      <description>Getting started with Unity So you managed your way through the Introduction and are still here. Awesome! The first step on your Journey to learn is to actually go and download Unity. While you could just head to unity3d.com and grab the latest and greatest Version of Unity Personal, I would suggest getting the Unity Hub. Unity Hub will help you manage your Projects as well as the Versions of Unity you have installed on your machine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>